hdrinc.com 2019-06-25

# Privacy | HDR

Last Revised on December 5, 2018

HDR is committed to privacy. Before providing us with any of your details, please read the following important information that concerns the protection of your personal information.

HDR, Inc. (1917 S. 67th Street, Omaha, NE 68106-2973, USA) and its family of companies ("HDR," “we,” or “us”) acknowledge and honor the privacy of visitors of [www.hdrinc.com](http://www.hdrinc.com/) (the “Website”). This privacy statement describes how your personal information will be treated in connection with your use of our Website. By continuing to use the Website you signify that you have read and understood this statement.  

For more information regarding HDR’s privacy practices for data received offline in the normal course of business, please contact us.

## Type of Information We Collect

### Information you submit to HDR though the Website

You may choose to give HDR personal information about yourself through the Website as noted below. If you wish to contact HDR without revealing such personal information, please contact us as detailed below.

Through the Website, HDR may collect the following types of personal information:

  * contact information;
  * company information;
  * photos, areas of expertise; 
  * resume and applicant information for those applying to job openings; and
  * other personal information you may provide.

If you elect to subscribe to an HDR enewsletter or provide your information to get a download of information or another web page, we will also ask you to provide at a minimum your name and email address. You will have the option to unsubscribe through the unsubscribe mechanism at the bottom of emails, or you can contact us and request to not be emailed.

### Through Use of the Website

The Website also automatically collects certain information about your use of the Website, such as the device used to access the Website, location information, browsing actions and patterns on the Website, traffic data, logs, resources accessed, search queries on the Website, IP address, operating system and browser type. We may collect this information directly or through third-party technologies (e.g., Google Analytics and/or other marketing and social media scripts).

**Cookies, Web Beacons and Other Tracking Technologies**

With your consent, to the extent required by applicable law, the Website also uses first and third-party cookies (or other similar tracking technologies) (collectively, “Cookies”) on the Website. Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your computer or device when you visit a website. We use the following Cookies on the Website:

**Strictly Necessary Cookies** \- These Cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the Website and completing requests on the Website. 

**Performance Cookies** \- These Cookies collect information about how you use the Website, for instance, which pages you go to most often, how long you stay and your path through the Website pages.  These Cookies are used to improve how the Website works and help us gather data to improve functionality or retention on the Website. 

**Functionality Cookies** \- These Cookies allow the Website to remember choices you make (e.g., saved searches, links to relevant content), language or the region you are in, and provide enhanced, more personal features to better reflect your particular interests, priorities, and preferences. These cookies do not track your browsing activity on other websites.

You may disable certain Cookies by changing the settings on your browser. Please refer to your browser options or other browser instructional materials to learn more about cookie management. You can also find more information about Cookies and how to manage them at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

Please remember that if you disable certain Cookies, it is likely to affect how the Website works and you may not be able to access or use certain areas or functionalities on the Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse all cookies, HDR’s system will place cookies when you log on to the Website, to the extent permitted by applicable law. At this time, we do not have the capability to honor web browsers' Do Not Track signals.

Our Website also includes social media (including Facebook, LinkedIn, and Twitter) share buttons which you may choose to use. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These features are hosted by a third party. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Use of Your Information

When you provide HDR with personal information about yourself, we may use the information for the following purposes: (1) respond to and otherwise facilitate your questions, comments, and requests; (2) provide and improve the Website to deliver a better and more personalized service; (3) send you HDR publications and enewsletters you have signed up for; and (4) maintain the security of the Website.

### Sharing Your Information

HDR may share your personal information with its subsidiaries, affiliates, and third-party contractors and vendors, for the purposes of processing such information on behalf of HDR to provide the Website and services requested. Except as described in this privacy statement and as otherwise permitted by law, HDR will only provide your personal information to any other third parties for other purposes when you, the visitor, specifically request information from that third party.

HDR may also share personal information as authorized or required by applicable law, including making disclosures that are necessary or advisable to: (1) protect the rights, health, safety, or property of HDR or others; (2) allow for lawful national security-related or law enforcement investigations; (3) comply with applicable laws, regulations, or other lawful requirements; and (4) in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business.

Except as stated in this privacy statement, HDR will not transfer, exchange, license, sell, lease, or otherwise disclose your personal information without your approval; however, HDR may collect and/or provide aggregated and anonymized statistics about the Website to other parties.

**Jobs at HDR**

When you choose to post a resume to the careers section of the Website and apply to become part of the HDR team, please note that you will be taken to a third-party URL (hdr.taleo.net) and these pages will be branded as HDR. The personal information you provide via the URL will be used solely for the purposes for which it is provided (including the processing of your application) and will be retained for such period as is necessary to comply with HDR’s legal and administrative requirements.

**Transfer of Information Overseas**

HDR is a global organization and personal information collected through the Website and affiliated websites such as Taleo may be shared with affiliates, subsidiaries, and third-party contractors and vendors outside your country of residence, such as the United States, for the purposes of providing the Website and services. You acknowledge that laws on the processing and transfer of personal information in these third countries may be less protective than the privacy laws in the country where you are based.

**Children's Privacy**

The Website and services are not targeted at children under the age of 13. HDR does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If you believe we are in receipt of personal information about a child under age 13, please contact us as detailed below.. 

**Security**

The Website is not designed to store sensitive personal information such as financial or health information, so please do not provide HDR with such information through the Website. HDR takes the security of your personal information seriously and has implemented appropriate technical and organizational security arrangements to protect your personal information, but cannot assure that these measures will be sufficient to protect against any unauthorized efforts to access such information.

**Links to Third-Party Websites**

Please note that this Website may link to other non-HDR Internet websites (“Third-Party Websites”). When you use a link to visit a Third-Party Website, you will be subject to that website’s privacy and security practices, which may differ from HDR's practices. You should familiarize yourself with the privacy policy, terms of use, and security practices of the linked Third-Party Website before providing any personal information on that website. HDR does not control or monitor the practices of Third-Party Websites.

### Changes to Privacy Policy

This statement only applies to information collected and maintained by HDR. HDR reserves the right to modify these practices at any time. If HDR makes any material changes to this statement, HDR will comply with applicable legal requirements and update the Effective Date at the beginning of the statement. We encourage you to periodically review the Website and this statement so that you have the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Choice Correcting or Updating Your Information

You may make requests regarding the purposes for which your personal information is used, object to our use of your personal information, request access to your personal information to update or correct or delete it altogether. HDR will make a sincere effort to respond in a timely manner to your requests, in accordance with applicable law. We will retain and use your information for as long as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. We also reserve the right to take reasonable steps to authenticate your identity before providing such access.

### Contact Us

For questions regarding these Website privacy practices, and all other requests relating to how your personal information is processed by HDR, please contact our Data Protection Officer at privacy [at] hdrinc.com or by regular mail at HDR’s address for the United States:

HDR  
1917 S. 67th Street  
Omaha, NE 68106-2973

This statement applies to HDR, Inc., and its subsidiaries and affiliates. HDR, Inc. is the data controller and party responsible for this website. HDR, Inc.’s representative for purposes of the GDPR is HDR GmbH (Germany):

HDR GmbH  
Josef-Gockeln-Straße 10  
DE-40474 Düsseldorf  
datenschutz [at] hdrinc.com
